joydeep.nag@stonybrook.edu +1 (516) 864-9872

# **EDUCATION**

### STONY BROOK UNIVERSITY

M.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING Aug 2022 - Dec 2023 (expected) | New York, USA

#### **BITS PILANI**

B.E.(Hons) IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS

July 2016 - July 2020 | Rajasthan, India CGPA: 8.35

#### **GRADUATE**

Computer Networks Analysis of Algorithms

#### **UNDERGRADUATE**

Data Structures and Algorithms Machine Learning Neural Networks and Fuzzy Logic Object Oriented Programming Operating Systems

# **SKILLS**

### **PROGRAMMING**

Advanced

- Java C Python Medium
- (++

Beginner

• Scala • JavaScript

#### **TESTING FRAMEWORKS**

• Mockito • JUnit • xUnit

#### FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES

Data Science

- Keras NumPy SKLearn
- NLTK(Natural Language ToolKit)
- TensorFlow

### **Backend Development**

• Spring • SpringBoot • Flask

#### Frontend Development

• React • Redux

#### **SPOKEN LANGUAGES**

Fluent

• English • Hindi • Bengali

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **SALESFORCE** | Associate Member of Technical Staff

Feb 2021 - July 2022 | Hyderabad, India

- Wrote the entire backend for a new feature called Recurring Schedule which allows users to create recurrences of their required functionality which has hugely improved productivity.
- Worked on developing a high impact and scalable feature called ActionPlans to allow customers to plan out requirements with deadlines by creating blueprints and then assign tasks to users related to the requirements
- The backend framework was designed on REST principles using Java and Spring with stringent testing, having a code coverage of over 90%.
- It has had significant customer adoption, increasing by 12% in the last 3 quarters.

#### **CISCO** | Software Engineer 1

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021 | Bangalore, India

- Worked on creating an end to end workflow for automation of device performance analysis.
- This tool can remotely check the health and other important parameters for device condition without manual intervention which significantly increased productivity, reducing its end-to-end response timeline to the tune of around 65%.
- Created the backend framework to develop a scalable application using Java and SpringBoot

### J.P. MORGAN CHASE | SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

May 2019 - July 2019 | Bangalore, India

- Worked on backend Web development creating a web application based on RESTful architecture to create an automatic language translation tool.
- The web application was highly scalable resulting in workflow efficiency increase, reducing the turnaround time of the review process by about 89%.

### **PROJECTS**

### **OBJECT DETECTION IN AERIAL IMAGES** | CEERI PILANI

Jan 2019 - May 2019 | Pilani, India

- Created an efficient neural network which can classify objects in images based on UAV(unmanned aerial vehicles) data.
- The backbone implemented was a DetNet-59 with a ResNet classifier on top.
- To get DetNet weights, two approaches were used:- convert PyTorch weights to Keras or simply train on ImageNet directly.
- Performance was similar to 2 stage state-of-the art object detection models.

# PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an experienced Software Engineer in full stack development. I am highly motivated towards solving challenging technical problems using the latest tools and have an excellent grasp on data structures and algorithms, alongwith database design. I have strong communication and interpersonal abilities to be a valuable team member.